# **Bryan Ricafranca**

8203 Capobella, Aliso Viejo, CA 92656

Phone: 626-484-3170 E-Mail: neal.b.ricafranca@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryanricafranca

**Objective:** I am looking to use my 8+ years of sales and management experience to lead and inspire a sales team to achieve the highest levels of success. My goal is to build on the team member's personal goals and skills, align them with the company's vision and goals, and create a strong sales environment.

#### **Experience**

#### **Quick Bridge Funding, LLC**

#### Senior Sales Manager (October 2016 - Present)

Database management of over 5000 accounts, responsible for lead distribution and sales analytics based on KPIs and various sales metrics. In-house classroom training for onboarding of new hires, as well as ongoing call training for current sales team. I continue to manage a sales team of 12 representatives and lead/inspire them to achieve their personal and professional goals. We achieved 112% to the funded dollars goal for Q1 2019.

#### Sales Manager (February 2015 – October 2016)

Managed 10-person sales team. Strategized with individual reps on closing deals, pipeline management, and overall approach to indecisive customers. Tracked progress for the team on monthly/weekly/daily sales goals. Consistently achieved overall monthly sales goals as a company, averaging 97.9% to goal in revenue for the 2015 & 2016 fiscal years.

#### Relationship Manager/Team Lead (April 2013 – February 2015)

Managed portfolio of 300+ accounts. Provided working capital loans to small businesses across the US. Top sales performer in the company, competing with other lenders and winning the business based on relationship & quality of service. Lead a small sales team of 4, training and guiding them to higher achievement levels while managing my own database of accounts. As an individual contributor, I set the company record for most funded dollars in a quarter (\$4.5 million funded, 3rd Quarter 2014), leading the sales team that earned the OC Business Journal's #1 Fastest Growing Midsize Company in Orange County award.

#### inTRIMSic, Inc.

#### Sales Representative/Manager (August 2009 – January 2013)

Outside sales to various garment and clothing manufacturers in Los Angeles and the surrounding areas. Cold calling, in-person visitation to buyers, wholesale manufacturers, and designers. Sold various trim items for different clothing lines. Led a 3-person sales team from January 2011 on to drive more company revenue.

### **Education**

Biola University (August 2004 - May 2008)

B.S. Degree in Biblical Studies

Q4 Psychological Associates Management Training (September 2016)

Various 2-day intensive management training sessions year-round centered on effective management and conflict resolution.

## **Skills**

- Consultative sales style
- 8+ years combined inside & outside sales experience
- Typing Speed: 71 WPM
- Database management
- Able to achieve goals in a fast-paced, results driven environment
- Inspirational and effective tactical floor leader
- Quick learner and excellent communicator
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook)
- CRM (Sage ACT!, Phoenix)
- Customer service